Strike Files of the U.S. Department of Justice, Pt. 1 on Microfilm 5897 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Casefile 16-145 End through 16-148 (Reel 18)
  - Casefile 16-154. Subjects 54. North Carolina, 1920; 18 (Reel 18)
    April 15-21. 1920. 38pp. Subject: Citizen support for DOJ efforts to break "outlaw" railroad strike. Begins at 1168.
  - [New Orleans, Louisiana, Railway Strike] Casefile 16-148, 1920; 19 (Reel 18)
    July 3-August 24, 1920. 24pp. Subjects: U.S. Marshal explanation of expenses and deployment of special deputies guarding railway property; strikebreakers; violence and intimidation; Amalgamated Association of Street and Electric Railway Employees; contract negotiations; open shop versus closed shop issues; arbitration and use of injunctions in labor disputes. Begins at 1206.
  - [New Orleans, Louisiana, Maine Iron Workers] Casefile 16-148, 1920; 20 (Reel 18)
    June 24-July 13, 1920. 18pp. Subjects: U.S. Shipping Board; use of injunctions in labor disputes; violence and intimidation. Begins at 1230.
- Casefile 16-130 (Reel 19)
  - Casefile 16-130. Subjects 13, Enclosure Section. Colorado, 1919; 1 (Reel 19)
    1919. 49pp. Subjects: Colorado Workmen's Compensation Law of 1919 and Industrial Commission Law of 1915. Begins at 0001.
  - Casefile 16-130. Subjects 26, Enclosure Section. Illinois, 1917-1920; 2 (Reel 19)
    1917-1920. 682pp. Subjects: U.S Supreme Court cases; Lever Act; Sherman Antitrust Act; constitutional law; government regulation of coal prices; alleged profiteering by coal companies; Majority and Minority Reports of the U.S. Bituminous Coal Commission to the president; DOJ prosecution of UMWA leadership; U.S. v. Frank J. Hayes, et. al. legal documents and transcript of proceedings; use of injunctions in labor disputes; Report to Governors of Six New England States on Present Fuel Crisis in New England; DOJ press relations; list of UMWA members denied reinstatement by coal companies; newspaper clippings; American Wholesale Coal Association; agreement between the Director General of Railroads and the Fort Worth and Denver City Railway Company; statement of contacts for production of railroad coal; UMWA contract negotiations; "The Coal Strike," issued by the Executive Committee of the Bituminous Coal Operators of the Central Competitive Field; UMWA order rescinding strike; U.S. Fuel Administration; U.S. Bituminous Coal Commission; "The Case of the Bituminous Coal Mine Workers," as presented by the UMWA; Hillsboro Coal Company and Rice Miller v. Edward C. Knotts legal documents; U.S. v. James M. Armstrong, et al. transcript of proceedings, vol. 1. Begins at 0050.
- Casefile 16-130. Continued (Reel 20)
  - Casefile 16-130. Subjects 26, Enclosure Section. Illinois cont, 1920; 1 (Reel 20)
    1920. 656pp. Subjects: Lever Act; Sherman Antitrust Act; constitutional law; DOJ prosecution of UMWA leadership of special assistant in case: U.S. v James M. Armstrong, et al. transcript of proceedings, vols. 2-4; National Coal Association v. Peyton Gordon legal documents. Begins at 0000.
  - Casefile 16-130. Subjects 29, Enclosure Section. Kansas, 1919; 2 (Reel 20)
    1919. 14pp. Subjects: Operation of coal mines by the state of Kansas; Kansas v. Mallams-Halstead Coal Company, et al. legal documents; Southwestern Interstate Coal Operators Association pamphlet "Do You Know! The Strike History of District No. 14 from August 1916-December 31, 1918." Begins at 0656.
  - Casefile 16-130. Subjects 57, Enclosure Section. Ohio, 1920; 3 (Reel 20)
    1920. 26pp. Subjects: U.S. Fuel Administration; U.S. Railroad Administration; The Raleigh Coal and Coke Company, et al. v. Harry A Worcester legal documents. Begins at 0670.
  - Casefile 16-130. Subjects 79, Enclosure Section. Ohio, 1920; 4 (Reel 20)
    1920. 26pp. Subjects: Financial Statement of the Borderland Coal Company. Begins at 0696.
  - Casefile 16-130. Subjects 83, Enclosure Section. West Virginia, 1919-1921; 5 (Reel 20)
    1919-1921. 140pp. Subjects: UMWA District 29 agreement with the New River Coal Operators Association; statements of Harry Olmstead and the Coal Investigating Committee; violence and intimidation in Mingo County, West Virginia; governor of West Virginia's declaration of martial law; refusal by coal operators to recognize UMWA; "The Issue in the Coal Fields of Southern West Virginia: Statements to President Harding by the Operators of the Williamson Field and the Logan County Coal Operators Association"; Borderland Coal Corporation, at el. v. UMWA, et al. Legal documents; use of injunctions in Labor Disputes. Begins at 0701.